Finding Aid for the National Association of Composers, U.S.A. records PASC-M.0080
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1. Scores, 1950-1986
  - Subseries 1.2. Unnumbered scores, 1950-1986
    - Fletcher, Grant: Stennos. Words by John Donne, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fletcher, Grant: Two Mexican Songs. For medium high voice and piano. Text by Max Brand, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fletcher, Grant: Zortzicos II. For string bass and piano, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Frye, Christopher: Trivium. For flute, oboe, violin and piano in three movements, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Garcia, Orlando J.: Constructs. For contra bassoon and piano, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Garcia, Orlando J.: Movement. For percussion, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Garcia, Orlando J.: Rhythmic Stratifications, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Garone, Jerry: Sonata, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Glazier, Beverly: Akdamut, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Glazier, Beverly: Currents. For flute, cello, piano, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Glazier, Beverly: Maduah Yehudi. Flute and cello, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Glazier, Beverly: Woman of Valor, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Glazier, Beverly: Women of Vision. clarinet, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Glesser, Frederic: Dazyes Duo. For horn and percussion, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Granet, John Nicholas: Eschaton I, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Granet, John Nicholas: Growing Up an' All That Stuff. Text by Suzanne Weiss, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Groudine, Vladimir: Toccata Op.28. For the piano, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Gwiazda, Henry: Now the Heart Song Cycle. For voice and piano, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Herron, J.: 5 Miniatures. For flute, violin, guitar, and piano. 5 copies, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hodkinson, Sydney: Refractions. For piano solo, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hoffman, David: Lamentation of Job, The. For mixed chorus a cappella, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hoover, Jeffrey: The Enigma, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Hoover, Jeffrey: The Lord's Prayer, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Hoover, Jeffrey: Quo Vadis (Whether Thou Goest), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Hunkins, Arthur B.: Fantasy. For piano, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Husa, Karel: Elegie. Pour piano, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Husa, Karel: Elegie et Rondeau. Pour saxophone alto et orchestre, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Husa, Karel: Poem. Fuer viola und kammerorchester, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Husa, Karel: Serenade. Pour quintette a vent solo et orchestre a cordes, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Husa, Karel: Streichquartett. Fuer 2 violinen, viola und violoncello, Op. 8, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Ishii, Maki: Black Intention. For one recorder player, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ishii, Maki: Black Intention II, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Keane, David: Elegy. For double bass and tape recorder, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Keane, David: Kaleidophon. For flute, clarinet, trombone, viola and cello, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Keane, David: Missa Mihi. For midrange female voice and string quartet, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Keane, David: Rainbow. For percussion and dancer, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Keane, David: Sinfonia. For violin, cello, piano and tape recorder, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Koch, Frederick: 12/12 For Two Pianos, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Koch, Frederick: Recollections in Penetralia for Two Pianos and Harp, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Kramer, Jonathan D.: Music For Pianos. Numbers 1,2,3, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Leibow, Ruth: Trio for violin, viola, and cello, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lindsey, David C.: Reconstructed Prophecies III. For flute, oboe, bassoon and piano, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Lindsey, David C.: Reconstructed Prophecies II, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Lindsey, David C.: String Quartet #1. The Gospel of Matthew, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - MacInnis, Don: Toccata. For piano and two- channel tape, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Maderich, Robert J., II.: Life's Cycle. A song cycle for soprano, cello, clarinet, and piano. Cello and clarinet, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Maderich, Robert J., II.: Three Movements. For clarinet, cello and piano, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Michalsky, Donal R.: Fantasia. For piano solo, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Michalsky, Donal: Four Short Piano Pieces, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Montague, Stephen: E Pluribus Unum, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Montague, Stephen: Paramell. For muted trombone and piano, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Montague, Stephen: Paramell V. For two pianos, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Montague, Stephen: Sotto Voce, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Moylan, William: Street Songs Volume I. For voice (any range). Text by Laurence d'A.M. Glass, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Oakes, Rodney: Chamber Music for Seven Players, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Oakes, Rodney: Legacy. For prepared tape and trombone, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Oakes, Rodney: Sonata. For brass, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Ordansky, Jerold: Four Songs From Paradise Lost, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ortiz, William: Composicion. Para violin, violoncello, y piano, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Ortiz-Alvarado, William: Musica. Para 2 v'chelos, flauta, y clarinete., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Ortiz, William: Sonatina. Para piano., 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Ortiz, William: Street Music (Musica de la Calle), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Ott, Joseph: Matrix 2. For 2 pianos, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Owen, Blythe: Toccata Op.21, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Pizer, Hayden, and Elizabeth Faw: String Quartet, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Read, Gardner: Touch Piece, Op. 85, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Reale, Paul: Salon Music, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Ballad, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: First Love in May, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Mazurka, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Mazurka, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Nocturne I, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Prelude I, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: The Sea. Concert etude, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Song of the Sea, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Variations on a Game, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reddy, Raymond Michael: Venetian Berceuse, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reed, H. Owen: For the Unfortunate, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Rochberg, George: Variations on an Original Theme. For piano solo, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sacco, P. Peter: Piano Concerto No.1. For large orchestra and piano, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sacco, P. Peter: Piano Sonata No.1, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sacco, P. Peter: Sonata No.2, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Saragoza, Justin: 4 Improvisations. Work No.32, no.7, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: 4 Tone Poems. Work No.36, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Assorted Studies: Study No.4. For 6 videotapes and independent sound source. Distributed in outer space, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Boulder Dam and Vacinity [sic]. For electric guitar and electric string quartet. Work No.55., 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Four Haiku. Improvisations for speaker, piano and string quartet. Work No.52, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Four Women. For piano, violin and cello, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Improvisation. For solo piano, guitar and female speaker. Work No.32, end piece, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Improvisation for 2 Dancers (2 stereo turntables and solo violin), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Improvisation No.1. For piano and guitar. Work No.32, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Improvisation No.4. For solo piano. Work No.32, no.5., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Improvisation No.5. For violin and cello. Work No.32, no.6., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Mystical Unicorns. For soprano and piano. Words by Kelly L. Dodson. Song No.10, work no. 61, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Piano Sonata No.2. Derived from "Source Sets for Theatre Pieces - Book 1", 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Shroud of Turin. Portion of work no.18, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Sonata, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Sonata for Orchestra No.2. (Symphony No.6). Work No.48, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Song No. 2, Work No.61, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Stained Glass. Work No.49, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: String Quartet. Work No.34, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Theatre Piece No.11. Work No.45, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Theatre Piece No.12 [0 thru 11 (mod 12)]. (After the Sky Turns Red), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Theatre Piece No.13. In three acts. Work No.47, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Untitled. Nos.1-8. Work No.39, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Variations for orchestra. Work No.50, no.1, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Saragoza, Justin: Variations on Suspended Animation. Words by Kelly L. Dodson, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Schooley, John: Choral Responses. For the Contemporary Worship Service, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: From a Very Little Sphinx. Poem by Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: I Love Them. For mezzo soprano or contralto and piano, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: Serenata. For tuba and piano, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: A Revelation of John. From Songs of Victory in Heaven, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: Two Short Sacred Songs: Praise Our God and Happy Are Those. For soprano. From Songs of Victory In Heaven., 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: Vocalise. For soprano, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Schooley, John: Winter's Journey. For baritone, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Selbst, George: Quartet in G, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Selbst, George: Quintet. For piano, two violins, viola, cello, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Selbst, George: Quintet in A Minor, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Shelton, Margaret Meier: Creation, a Symphony. For mezzo-soprano and alto flute, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Shelton, Margaret Meier: Fullness of Time, A. For mezzo-soprano and alto flute, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Shelton, Margaret Meier: When the Sun Has Set, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Snow, David: Effluvia. A chamber concerto for nine instruments (Winner of 1977 BMI Award to Student Composers), undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Snow, David: String Trio (1979 BMI Award to Student Composers), circa 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Snyder, James: EFF. For two Bb clarinets and violoncello. Score in C, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Steinke, Greg A.: Six Pieces. For pianoforte 1963-1964 (revised from Suite for Piano, 1962) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Takahashi, Yuji: Metatheses 2, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Takahashi, Yuji: Three Poems of Mao Tse-Tung, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Tashjian, Charmian: Armenechos. For alto flute, bass clarinet, violoncello, vibraphone, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Tashjian, Charmian: Songs. For chorus and brass sextet, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Tashjian, Charmian: Songs of the Sea. For mezzo soprano, viola and piano. On poems by Longfellow, William Carlos Williams, Hopkins, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: Caprice Elegant. For flute and accordion, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: The Dorn Dance. For saxophone, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: Interchange 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: Sonata. For guitar, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: Sonata. For unaccompanied violin, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: Suite. For double bass, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tautenhahn, Gunther: Three Miniatures. For cello, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tereszkiewicz, Tom: Internal Motion, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Unknown: Sonata With Some Pine Trees. For oboe, three percussionists and double bass, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Unknown: Trumpet, Horn, Trombone, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Unknown: untitled pieces, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Van Appledorn, Mary Jeanne: Matrices, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Includes 1 compact audio cassette.
    - Van de Vate, Nancy: Letter to a Friend's Loneliness. For soprano and string quartet, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Van de Vate, Nancy: Trio. For bassoon, percussion and piano, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Vickers, Carlton Joseph: Chenrazee. Meditation for drums (Opus 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Vickers, Carlton Joseph: Helix. Opus 5 for flute unaccompanied (3 pieces), undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Vogt, Hans: Sonata Alla Toccata. Fuer Klavier, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Von Webern, Anton: Quintet. For string quartet and piano, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Wallace, Ishmael: Serenade. For wind ensemble, piano and double bass, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, Ishmael: Seven Songs. To texts from Christian Morgenstern's Galgenlieder, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, Ishmael: She Appears to Me, Present. Four songs for mezzo-soprano and piano, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, Ishmael: Sonata. For cello and piano, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, Ishmael: Saint Anthony of the Fire, or: Havoc in Hell. An opera based on a Sardinian folk tale, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Wallach, Joelle: Cords (1972-73). For soprano and two string basses, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Welmstead, John: Quintessence. For five brass instruments, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wheeler, Scott: Piece for five players, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Wheeler, Scott: Singerie, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Wheeler, Scott: Trio (1983). For violin, cello and piano (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Williams, Janet Eliza: Sonata. For flute and percussion, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Ziffrin, Marilyn J.: Suite for piano, Op. 4, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Series 2. Organizational materials, 1933-1988; 1958-1980
  This series contains the organizational materials of both the NAACC and NACUSA. Included are membership materials and rosters, meeting minutes, chapter information, financial reports, newsletters, and correspondence. Also included are clippings, concert programs and calendars, and event announcements and invitations. Much of this material was maintained by recording secretary Naomi Reynolds, to whom a large part of the correspondence is addressed, and to whom member composers sent concert programs, clippings, and news of their accomplishments, for inclusion in Reynolds' "Prospect and Retrospect" column in the NACUSA newsletter, Composer/USA. Reynolds' notes and planners are also included here. This series also includes five volumes of scrapbooks containing ephemera from the organization's various activities.
  - NAACC membership and committees, 1959-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - NAACC published rosters, 1959-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NAACC events and membership information, 1960-1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - NAACC Albert Goldberg tribute luncheon invitation design, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - NAACC Los Angeles chapter meeting minutes, 1960-1975 (Box 9, Folder 4-17)
    Organization and Arrangement
    Folders are arranged by year.
  - NAACC Treasurer's Reports, 1963-1975 (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
  - NAACC newsletter. Composer and Conductor, 1960 September-1975 July (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - NACUSA bylaws research and final draft, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - NACUSA stationery proofs, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - NACUSA Los Angeles chapter meeting minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - NACUSA membership information for chapters, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - NACUSA Chicago chapter, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - NACUSA New York chapter, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - NACUSA Philadelphia chapter, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - NACUSA San Antonio chapter, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - NACUSA concert material, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - NACUSA Treasurer's Reports, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - NACUSA membership in California Confederation of the Arts, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - NACUSA California Arts Council communication, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - NACUSA newsletter Composer/USA, 1975 October-1984 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Naomi Reynolds "Prospect and Retrospect" column drafts (Composer/USA), 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Promotional material for NACUSA member composers, 1968-1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Event invitations, 1959-1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Courses, workshops, and competitions, 1969-1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
    Much of this correspondence is addressed to recording secretary Naomi Reynolds, to whom member composers sent concert programs, clippings, and news of their accomplishments, for inclusion in Reynolds' "Prospect and Retrospect" column in the NACUSA newsletter, Composer/USA. Also included are correspondence between other members, including organization presidents Ernest Gold and John Vincent.
  - Concert programs, calendars, and announcements, 1958-1972 (Box 11, Folder 11-15)
  - Concert programs, calendars, and announcements, 1973-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
  - Newsletters and bulletins from other organizations, 1962-1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1979 (Box 14, Folder 6-15)
  - Naomi Reynolds notes and work materials, 1933-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Naomi Reynolds planners and agendas, 1953-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - John Vincent CV and career material, ca. 1959-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - All That Jazz: A Bibliography of Book on Jazz and Its Antecedents with Special Reference to the Holdings of the Library at CSU Dominguez Hills, ed. Louis N. Bell, 1979 March (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - CSU Dominguez Hills Japanese Music Collection: 1979 report, 1977-1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - CSU Dominguez Hills Japanese Music Collection: music orders, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - CSU Dominguez Hills Japanese Music Collection: grants, fellowships, and other funding, 1976-1979 (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
  - CSU Dominguez Hills Japanese Music Collection: "New Electronic Music/ Japan" concert, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbooks, 1956-1970 (Box 16, Box 17, Box 18)
    Five volumes.